# Killian Jochen McShane

# Computer Science Student

killian.jmcshane@gmail.com
github.com/killianmcshane
linkedin.com/in/killianmcshane
killianmcshane.github.io
+44 7821745056

Third-year student of computer science at The University of Liverpool, specialising in artificial intelligence and data science. Proficient in R, Python, Java, SQL, and functional Haskell programming languages with experience using software development and data analysis tools such as Apache Ant, Power BI and Tableau. I am highly IT and Mathematically literate, with a strong background in customer-facing roles.

### Education

### **BSc (Hons) Computer Science**

The University of Liverpool

09/2018 - Present

First Class (Expected)

### Career

#### **Information Analyst**

The Walton Centre NHS

10/2021 - Present

Liverpool

- Provided actionable insight to recommend opportunities and improvements through analytics.
- Developed predictive modelling, clinical and patient flow algorithms for statistical data analysis.

#### **Customer Service Representative**

The Royal Bank of Scotland

10/2017 - 03/2018

Belfast

- High-pressure environment with heavy call queues.
   Teamwork, exceeding KPI expectations and preventing escalations was necessary to succeed.
- Asking pertinent questions and empathetically delivering help was key to resolving issues quickly.

## Customer Service Representative

Teleperformance UK

10/2016 - 04/2017

Newry

- Handled and managed customer complaints.
- Clarified payment options and credit management.

# Data Analysis Spring Internship

FM Environmental

04/2015

Newry

- Analysed and processed friction and fluid calculations.
- Graphed insights from data analysis using Excel to relay information to engineers.

### Languages

• English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

German

Professional Working Proficiency

### Skills



### Achievements

# Founder & President of The Data Science and Artificial Intelligence Society at The University of Liverpool

I manage the society and the organisation of the group as a whole. My leadership involves chairing meetings, attracting funding, and managing relationships with stakeholders.

#### BT Young Scientist Boot Camp (2015)

Selected for and won the competition. Lead a team of 5 individuals through the development lifecycle of a new product.

#### <u>Interests</u>

Boxing Running		Mather	matics
Deep Learning Big		Data	Crypto & Blockchain

## **Projects**

- Exploratory Data Analysis on Branch Sales (Tableau)
   A presentation of insights from my analysis of raw CSV sales data.
- Bank Statement Classification & Data Analysis (Python)

  A Deep Neural (NLP) Network I trained on 12500 transactions.

  Includes an in-depth presentation of insights and predictions.
- Automated Build Deployment & Testing (Apache Ant)
   Build deployment using Apache Ant, Java, an XML build file, and JUnit.
- Short-term Stock Price Prediction Web-app (Python, JS)

  Prediction using an LSTM Neural Network & Twitter Sentiment Analysis.

...and many more on my GitHub profile.